Bitcoin needs to be in people's
portfolio because it is a hedge against
abundance. It cannot be destroyed
because it is built on beliefs. Beliefs
that it will have a store of value just
like gold except for one thing. It's
digital. And so I think everyone needs
to adjust their views. And my job has
always been I'm going to keep quiet on
Bitcoin until the tape tells me that
it's time to be loud again. It's time to
be loud again.
>> What's going on guys? Today we have a
great conversation with Jordy Visser.
And boy is this one fun. We talk about
Bitcoin and the 22% surge this week in
the price. What's driving it? Is it
sustainable? And how should you think
about Bitcoin in your portfolio? We also
talk about Stripe, Ramp, Anthropic,
OpenAI, and many of the AI companies
that are embracing various aspects of
the industry. And then we talk about
what's going on with public companies
and why the multiples are compressing,
how competition is now such a cut-throat
part of this industry. And then we even
talk about how investors are going to
navigate all of the volatility, all of
the change, and where exactly will
Bitcoin end up over the coming months
and years. I hope you enjoy my latest
conversation with Jordy Visser.
All right, Jordy, Bitcoin is ripping
higher. A week ago, you said that the
prior two weeks were the two biggest
weeks in Bitcoin's history, potentially.
Here we are with Bitcoin now up 22% over
the last 7 days. Explain what has
happened and why you think that this is
a sustainable bull market now.
>> Well, when we talked two weeks ago, it
was the week after situational
awareness. It was the week after Kevin
Walsh did nothing and basically said the
bond market was doing the work for him
and then finished off that week with the
most important thing. And I I I do
believe the thing that most people um
either missed or for macro
people in general debating whether this
will work or not and that was the
intervention into the yen. It was the
beginning of what I would call
intervention and uh by Scott Bessant to
highlight in a contextual way with the
economy racing with stocks at all-time
highs and yet he felt the need to
intervene for the first time since 1998
in the yen in a way that basically said
we don't want yields going higher. Then
you have the quarterly refunding
announcement shortly after where they
change some language in there leading
into what happened this week which is a
change in the debt buyback. So rather
than everyone sit there and argue about
you know whether this is going to happen
or not I just want to remind people one
thing and I'm going to cover this
extensively in the video this weekend.
The tape doesn't lie and the one thing
that had been going on is despite
everything that was happening Bitcoin
was acting better. It was handling bad
news. We had the the hacking into a
wallet. We had Michael Sailor selling uh
Bitcoin. We had all kinds of negative
news. Clarity Act not getting through.
And yet it was still trading well. It
was hanging in there. The tape was
telling you that something different was
happening. But then when you get this
week, and everyone should go read the
expost that I've put out there. So far,
this is a seven sigma week in Bitcoin.
There's only been three in the last
decade that were greater than five. And
so people understand what a sigma week
is. Uh this is taking the movement of
Bitcoin for a weekly basis in this case
over 20% as of when we get on here about
23%.
And going through and dividing it by
what a normal weekly move would be.
And in this case, uh, a seven, you know,
we had a V, a 60-day V, which is what
I'm using for my actual sigma
calculation of 23. So, it's a daily
volatility. So, when you go through it,
you have basically a seven standard
deviation move. The prior two that were
above five, they happened in uh Janu uh
April of 19 and January of 23. And I
hate to say that those were the
beginnings or the end of the prior
four-year cycles uh since I've said on
here I don't subscribe to any four-year
cycle. But in this case, we are getting
the exact same sigma move. And in those
other two cases, believe it or not, we
also broke above the 200 day moving
average. So all that leads into
something I've said, which is I don't
care about even trying to pick the
bottom of this thing uh from a saying
it's positive until we break above the
200 day moving average. In both of those
prior times, we stayed above the 200 day
moving average going forward and Bitcoin
started leading to a very large rally. I
happen to think with all of the things
that we've talked about, the AI agents,
the fact that the government is showing
that they want to run things hot, you
have a secretary, a Treasury secretary
who is quoting Satoshi in Expos. You
have Kevin Walsh who is a Bitcoin lover.
you have everybody in the administration
that people should be paying attention
that something more important is going
on here as the financial guard rails of
the agentic world are starting to play
out and I'll leave with one more thing
which we can either talk about or not
but I'm spending a lot of time with what
Stripe is doing and my whole thesis is
that the merging of AI and crypto and
for Bitcoin it will always be the purest
AI trade at a time where we have AI I
not working as well as people want it
to, getting frustrated, and you have a
move in Bitcoin, which is 23% in a very
short amount of time.
>> Before we get to Stripe, uh, Bitcoin
itself feels like there's a couple of
key components here. Um, earlier this
week, I recorded a podcast and was
asked, you know, what are my thoughts
about Bitcoin and why it's been so
stable? And I explicitly called out the
fact that I didn't see a catalyst on the
calendar. It wasn't obvious where the
catalyst was going to come from. This
seems like a very big kind of surprise
announcement from the Treasury. Now I
think you understood kind of what was
happening with the yen and the fact that
there were likely would have to do
something etc. But I think to the
general market, they were not expecting
the treasury to come in with, you know,
kind of doubling of uh of the capital
going in here. And you see this the
stock market, Bitcoin, everything, you
know, kind of rallying in response. And
so I guess part of this is if you go and
you look at these past moves, uh
Raphael, who's one of the co-founders of
Glass Node, he did the analysis and said
in the past there's been about 14
different five uh sigma moves or larger.
the forward return off of those moves
over the next 6 months was 80%
appreciation. So, put aside for a
second, 80% sounds like a great number.
Who knows, you know, uh uh kind of how
[clears throat] specific the numbers,
but just a very large move happens after
that. Do you put any weight on the vibe
shift and the feeling that it kind of
like awoken the Bitcoin community and
all of a sudden you see the persistent
bid this week is going to be one of the
biggest ETF inflow weeks uh since the
all-time high Bitcoin price. Like it
just feels like the world kind of got
shaken awake and reminded Bitcoin is the
answer to this government undisiplined
monetary policy.
>> So I think that's probably the way the
community um thinks about it. I think
that the thing that matters the most for
this particular move is getting
traditional finance people involved. And
this is where from my lens, like
everything that you said is a lens that
would have been used by the Bitcoin
community over the last decade. From my
lens and my seat in talking to hedge
fund people and mutual fund people and
let's say the majority of people being
above the age of 45 that have already
made a lot of money in their life.
That's not what I'm hearing. Um, I I'm
hearing more about the fundamentals
associated with the financial
guardrails. I'm hearing more about what
was discussed at the White House and
everyone there. I'm hearing more about
what is figure. I mean, I we talked
about figure I included in my video last
week. That's there. You have the 13F
filing news with Stan Duck Miller
basically buying into crypto, Bitcoin
miners, and some other parts of the
ecosystem like Hyperlid. Like the
financial guardrails are changing. And
when you have one of the greatest
investors of all time who is uh on the
higher end of the age scale who believes
in what's happening who believes in the
financial guard rails that is the
underpinning and this is the reason why
I do the videos is the reason why we
started doing this is I believe these
two systems were going to merge and
people were going to start to realize
that Bitcoin is not some thing. It's not
it's not it's not a it's random thing.
It's attached to crypto. It's where
crypto was born. It's the white paper.
It's what Mark Andre wrote about when he
put in why Bitcoin matters. All of that
is now here. And if you go back to that
that Andre piece, which I advise
everyone who has never read it, just go
pull it up on the internet and go read
it. I think it was January of 2014, why
Bitcoin matters and go through and
understand that everything that he wrote
in that paper, Mark Andrea, where he
called it the third most important
innovation in computer history,
why it matters and the fact that it
would take the next 20 years. He didn't
say 10. He didn't say 15. He said 20 by
2034. That aligns with AGI, that aligns
with AI agents, that aligns with
everything that the hedge fund community
will now be buying. In my side, I
believe and will continue to say it is
the purest AI trade with AI being
bringing us to abundance where it
destroys every single public company
growth. You the ability to grow, we're
watching it with anthropic and I think
it's just very insightful that the
fastest growing tech company in history
that is growing insanely. People start
getting worried about whether their ARR
is 65 billion or 75 billion or what the
number is. And I'm getting all these
text messages. this is the end of AI and
blah blah blah. No, it's not the end of
AI. It's not the end of anthropic. But
their growth rate will slow down
significantly because of competition.
Open source is competition. Open AI is
competition. Rockbot is competition.
Competition comes out of nowhere. So,
Bitcoin needs to be in people's
portfolio because it is a hedge against
abundance. It cannot be destroyed
because it is built on beliefs. Beliefs
that it will have a store of value just
like gold except for one thing. It's
digital. And so I think everyone needs
to adjust their views. And my job has
always been I'm gonna keep quiet on
Bitcoin until the tape tells me that
it's time to be loud again. It's time to
be loud again.
>> What I think is really interesting about
um maybe the intersection of AI and
Bitcoin is um AI to your point has hyper
competition. We are seeing now almost
every single day somebody is launching
something new, somebody's coming through
with some uh announcement of an
engineering breakthrough. Um, the
ability for companies to get more
intelligence at a lower cost is the
pursuit of almost every business I talk
with. They want to figure out how to
slash cost but continue to, you know,
benefit from this great technology. All
of that hyper competition
reminds me Bitcoin has no competition.
And I think that it's a very unique
thing because the framework that a lot
of folks have used including myself is
like if AI is about abundance and
there's going to be abundance of
information, abundance of intelligence,
abundance of content, etc. then scarcity
becomes valuable and you and I have
talked about, you know, Bitcoin being
that scarce asset. But it's also if
there's hyper competition, you know,
kind of the Peter Teal approach of like
you want to invest in monopolies, you
want to go invest where there is no
competition. He's got a famous talk
competition is for losers and bitcoin
you know stable coins have a different
use case there's you know tokenized uh
securities all these other kind of
assets but bitcoin itself has no
competition and that feels like that is
going to become only more valuable over
the next couple of years
>> this gets into competition to me when
it's infinite and it's happening in
seconds that's getting us closer to
abundance because what is intense
competition ition that comes out of
nowhere. If you run a business and
someone is able to do it at a cheaper
price, you are driving prices to zero.
This is the deflationary aspect of the
capitalist system. If it starts going
into hypers speed and what used to
happen in a month happens in a day or in
an hour or in a minute, then by
definition any idea that comes up get
there's a new one competing with it
immediately. Especially when the agents
are running. I did that whole thing last
week where I just said to people if you
have a digital agent they're shrinking a
year into 70 days just on the workload
side. They work constantly. So all of
this stuff when you line it up for
competition. You have to understand that
the way people are going to think two
years from now is how do I hedge against
everything that I own as a fiat asset
having extreme competition to where it
can't grow anymore? People invest in
growth assets. There are no growth
assets in my viewpoint anymore. When you
start moving to scarcity, well, it makes
sense that Micron should do well and go
through it. But ask anyone that's owned
Nvidia for the last two and a half years
how they feel. It has been a horrible
stock to own in the way people think.
And I hear this from every hedge
[clears throat] fund person. Nobody's
long Nvidia as like their big AI trade.
But since June of 24, so over two years,
Nvidia's up has compounded about 80%. It
sounds great, but there were only four
months where that entire gain happened.
Four months out of the 24. Aside from
that, it went sideways. And the reason
is because people think Nvidia is going
to have competition. Its earnings have
printed and yet the stock has been
lagging. That is the AI trade going
forward. The AI infrastructure trade
will still outperform the S&P. It is
still the place in the stock world that
you want to have a lot of your money.
But as I've talked about, I've moved on
to the application layer. I've moved on
to people living forever. I've moved on
to Eli Liy. I've moved on to the
scarcity side in silver, but also
Bitcoin. I still own things in
infrastructure. I still own Marll. I
still I have a little bit of Micron that
I purchased in in this down move. And I
still have other names with inside the
space as my equity holdings. But right
now, my overweights are towards the
scarcity trade because I believe the
basement was coming. But number two, if
we're right, if we're entering a point
where competition becomes the big thing,
I just think people are underestimating
how many people need to hedge the risk
of that. And that's the way to think
about Bitcoin. It's in a world of
abundance. That means hyper competition,
which means AI is winning. Remember what
happened to software companies in the
first quarter of the year and how it was
spreading like a disease across the
market. It's happening in the S&P 500
because multiples are compressing. It's
happening in the hyperscalers,
hyperscalers because multiples are
compressing. It's happening in Nvidia
now. It's going to happen in all of the
AI trade including Micron include all of
these. They will see multiple
compression over the next three years
because behind them for scarcity is
humanoids coming. People are not paying
attention to how quickly you're going to
be able to go to a race to zero for the
cost of running a business and how
quickly you can compete and you're going
to be left with where do I put my money?
Well, the guard rails are just being
built. So, that's a growth asset. At the
same time, Bitcoin becomes the S&P 500
of the future. It is a stable value
investment that grows with the dollars
flowing into it that are moving from one
system which is old and has no growth
anymore into another system that is
taking that money and is still growing
positively.
>> So one of the things that I think is um
is very interesting about watching this
all happen is usually when multiples
compress and stocks either are stable
and grow and earnings continue to grow
or the stock price itself falls then
people get excited. Hey, I can buy this
thing for a cheaper valuation than I
could a week, you know, a month ago,
three months ago. What you're really
issuing is maybe a warning that says
just because multiples are compressing
does not mean that the market is being
irrational and therefore it is a buying
opportunity. You're actually really
making the argument that the multiple
compression is a sign that the market is
nervous about future competition and the
ability for these companies to be
resilient. Is that a fair
characterization of the multiple
compression?
>> Yeah. And and combining that from a you
know a a let's say a fundamental
perception of fiat assets you have two
things which are also shrinking. One is
terminal value. So you don't know you
know if if the competition is growing
then multiple compression to me
represents the risk that in 3 years
there's actually no growth anymore. So
if you if if your whole thing about the
value and why something should trade at
23 time why should something trade at 20
times earnings and not one times
earnings? Why shouldn't Well, this is
all the leverage in the system and this
is all the belief that there'll be
terminal value in the future discounted
cash flows. If you don't know 3 years
from now whether you're going to be in
business or forget going out of
business, just not having growth. Nobody
invests in something that isn't growing.
People want to invest in things that are
growing. I don't believe that 3 years
from now anyone can have certainty
whether it is Adobe on the obvious side
or Micron on the side that looks dirt
cheap. I don't know if there won't be
competition three years ago and I know
this nobody does. So at some point the
probability of there being no value to a
company 5 years from now, 7 years from
now, 8 years from now, you take those
discounted cash flows from that point on
and you pro produce a lower uh a lower
valuation or lower probability of them
actually being there, you compress the
pees. And that's what's happening to me
and that's what's going to continue to
happen on the leverage side. The fiat
system is based on everinccreasing
leverage. I believe because of the
volatility that we've seen in these
stocks, each company's volatility has
gone through the roof. Micron is trading
at four times Bitcoin's volatility.
Think about that. If you take the 60-day
V for Bitcoin, it just finished last
week at 24. 60-day realized V micron
120. You can't own as much micron as you
can Bitcoin right now cuz it's less
volatile. So the whole world has gone
topsyturvy. And what that says to me is
Bitcoin is a safer investment than a
company three years from now. And
because of that, when you start to go
through this, you have to question how
your portfolio is, how you're invested
in it. I think hedge fund leverage has
peaked and will forever go down. And the
[snorts] point is that I don't think the
volatility difference that's happening.
There's no way to hedge this risk in the
stock side. The only way to hedge things
is to move money into an asset which
benefits from the volatility in the
competition. And that gets us back into
things that are b based on scarcity and
are going to benefit from AI. To finish
off again, I've talked about silver
before. Silver is the perfect cross
thing. It fits in with the gold thing.
It fits in with the the uh monetary
asset replacement, but it is a mineral
that is needed for all AI and we have a
shortage of it. So that is the reason
why at this point when I think we're
entering a point where gold, silver, and
bitcoin are going up together. It's not
just a debasement trade. It is a
scarcity trade. you have to be worried
about competition on the other side of
your portfolio.
>> Now, there's a lot of different ways to
think about Bitcoin in a portfolio.
Obviously, people who go on TV and, you
know, frankly, have either no conviction
or scared because their lawyer told them
to be careful, they'll say, "Oh, you
should put 1 to 2% of your portfolio in
Bitcoin." Um, if you go and you talk to
maybe uh somebody who's got a more macro
view, they'll say 6040 is broken. You
could go 60% equities, 40% Bitcoin, and
replace your bonds with Bitcoin. And
then if you go to the hardcore Bitcoin
maximalist, they'll tell you, "Why would
you own anything including, you know, a
table, a chair, a car, a house, or a
dollar? You should just have 100% of all
your wealth in Bitcoin." How do you
think about, you know, if building a
portfolio for yourself or for others in
terms of is Bitcoin something that is a
very small percentage and is more of,
you know, a replacement for a single
name stock? Is it kind of a a larger
percentage and a replacement for
something like bonds? Is it the entire
portfolio? just walk through maybe the
the framework you would use for people
to think through how Bitcoin fits into
that portfolio.
>> Okay. So, I'm going to answer this um
two ways. First, I'm going to bring
Sylvia into it. What What would Sylvia
say? Like you Sylvia is going to
customize to the person, right?
And for that to work, the person needs
to talk about the risk it wants. It has
to be based on how they spend money,
what they want their lifestyle to be,
how young they are, how healthy they
are. Um Rick Edelman, you've interviewed
him, right? I mean, he made the argument
that uh you know, people should have
more because they're going to live
longer. Well, what did Maderna
come out with this week? What news hit
the market that made a stock more than
double in a day? Uh something I know
we've talked about and I even said it
already in this show,
people won't die from disease at some
point in the future. And when when it
gets cheap enough that everyone can have
that, we're getting to the point where
when you get to cancer in particular
where you can say that there can be a
vaccine that they're making headway on
this for melanoma, which is a very
complicated cancer.
I people have to understand that would
mean, okay, I'm going to live longer. I
need more growth in my portfolio and
less bonds. Okay. Well, if I say there
are no growth assets anymore because AI
is destroying growth, then where do you
go? So, from my side, I am on the side
for the younger you are and the more you
want money to work for you, Bitcoin
breaks all of this stuff. It's the
purest AI trade. It's a time hedge. It's
an abundance hedge. It's all of these
things. And so if you have lots of money
and you've already made it and you're
older, I still think you should have a
lot more money in Bitcoin as an anti-day
side on the other side, which is the
assets that you own. But again, only if
you're focused on growth. I think it
needs to be part of the growth bucket. I
need think it needs to be aligned with
the risk that you're taking. And I think
that's a personal thing for everyone who
has their own money and decides. I know
for me
it's out of an asset allocation relative
to stocks and this it was the biggest
before the AI stuff started to
outperform Bitcoin and I'm sure if
Bitcoin does what I think it's going to
do it's going to be the largest but now
I have a lot more in silver and also
precious metals. So today's episode is
brought to you by Figure Markets. All
right everyone, who wants a slice of
$160,000?
Our partner figures running a promo
where they're giving back to their
community. From July 27th to August
27th, any user who has never completed a
cryptoback loan with them can qualify
for this giveaway. Check out the link in
my bio for more information. We're
living in a world of higher for longer
rates, tighter credit, and fewer places
to earn real yield. That's why Figure is
interesting. Figure is the largest
non-bank heliloc lender in the United
States with over $22 billion unlocked
for homeowners. They're now applying
that same concept and innovation to
cryptoback loans and realworld asset
yield. If you're holding crypto, Figure
let you borrow against it at 8.91%
interest, which is 9.999%
APR with a 50% loan to value, giving you
liquidity without selling, without
triggering taxes, and without stepping
out of the market. They use a
decentralized NPC custody so assets stay
in segregated wallets protected from rug
poles and they've introduced liquidation
protection to help manage downside
volatility. And for investors looking
for yield, Democratized Prime offers up
to 9% APY paid hourly backed by
realworld private credit, real cash
flows, and not speculative token
emissions. Figure is building a new
capital market on blockchain and now you
have access to the upside. Check them
out using the link below. Well, what
what I find very interesting is uh the
Madna news um is a good example where
you know again kind of an announcement
out of nowhere stock significantly
increases uh more than doubles in a day.
It obviously you know anytime a stock
does that it's going to cool a little
bit. It came down uh but today um as
we're recording this on Friday it's up
16% to start the day and so that is not
kind of announcement driven. That is
obviously the market trying to figure
out what is this worth, right? How real
is the phase three trial results? who is
this going to impact? What does this
look like from a revenue or earnings
potential, you know, a year from now,
etc. And so the other side of companies
quote unquote not growing is innovation.
And you've talked about like Eli Liy
heavily investing in AI and building out
these data centers and you know their
revenue is growing uh 50% year-over-year
as a trillion dollar company. But I do
think that part of uh the competition
story and the growth story is not only
external. Yes, the big model labs are
under pressure from, you know, everyone
from Kimmy K3 to Nvidia's open source
to, you know, every single company going
after specialized workflows and applied
AI, but they're also in competition with
themselves and the ability to kind of
constantly disrupt yourself. And I think
Madna is a great story where if you had
talked to people on Monday of this past
week, they would have said that
basically Madna had a bunch of legacy
assets from co that that was really the
value of that company. I don't think a
lot of people were pointing to it saying
like, "Oh, they're going to be where
innovation around cancer is going to
come from." And I heard Martin
Schrellley talk about the fact that a
lot of people had even abandoned the
idea of this specific uh phase trial and
and drug etc as not going to really, you
know, be something that worked. It's
innovation. It's, you know, competition.
It's disrupting yourself. And it does
feel like that is now the uh kind of
playbook every company's going to have
to follow if they want any fighting
chance to create value in the future is
they basically have to every 12 to 18
months figure out what do we want to be
when we grow up which is very different
than what they had to do in the past.
>> Yeah. Yeah, the Madna thing is um again
is something for everyone to make sure
they read about and understand the
importance of AI involved with this
getting over this hurdle and how this is
going to be a door opening for so many
cancer drugs, cancer treatments,
everything along those lines. Um there's
only one well actually no I know the
Lily one too but let's say the only
Dave Johnson who I assume is still with
Maderna. The only reason I know his name
is because I listen to many podcasts
with him when they and how AI helped
them figure out the vaccine so quickly
for co and that's when I started to
realize oh my gosh when we get to the
point where machine learning is
ubiquitous like it is today where we
have the model companies advancing so
advanced when al before that was done
before alpha fold three all of this
stuff you reach a point where you should
be able to take things from stage two
which is where things usually die in the
IP side in terms of getting through the
FDA approval. And with AI, AI, you
should be able to get that IP over the
finish line. So, biotech and pharma are
not growth industries cuz they're
moonshots. They can change overnight.
Um, I am going to show this weekend.
I've written a bunch of papers on
pharmaceuticals beginning in November of
last year about how they will eventually
be the biggest winners out of AI from
the application side. And I think that
is starting. Pharmaceuticals despite it
being a year where rates have gone
higher and they're usually sensitive to
rates and they're usually viewed as a
defensive sector. Well, healthcare has
outperformed the S&P by I think 7 8%
this year. It made new multi-year highs
on a relative basis. It's still way
below the all-time highs and I think
pharmaceuticals are going to be a place
that money is going into. I think the
entire healthc care field is some place
that AI is going to go into. So when we
look at these things and we think about
the way people view them both from an
investment standpoint and what you were
talking about in terms of people either
working for the companies, what's going
on, I do want to add one thing here that
fits in with you bringing up the
hyperscalers which we've talked about.
Um there are two economies right now.
One of them I call the AI native one but
I just want to say that that is the the
entrepreneurial economy and the other
one is the public companies.
The majority of talent is starting to
leave the public big bureaucracies and
move to the entrepreneurial economy. Uh
my son is going to be a junior in
college. He's seeing the power of being
an entrepreneur. He's seeing the ability
to do it. He and I talk all the time. I
told you about his chief of staff and
spinning out agents. Well, I just
created so many agents this week in
Grockbot. It blew my mind. like I used
it extensively over the last three days
and I'm doing the same thing that he's
doing and in a framework that is so much
easier than what I had to build in
OpenClaw and Hermes and it works there
and it's doing so many more things and I
trust it more that I think people have
to view that public companies which are
what they invest in
are losing the best talent and that's
the other switch that's going is I think
the more talented curious the less you
want to sit at a desk the less you get
frustrated by your boss the less you get
frustrated with your investors, come
over to our side, come over to the
entrepreneurial side and build things
and go through them. I think it's a
better place and I think you'll have
more fun. I think that's going to be the
other place that's draw people and
that's huge for
the crypto world because Stripe and all
of these companies that are private and
they talk about them, they have that
whole ecosystem there. They're growing
rapidly and that's why whenever they
publish something, when you go read the
numbers, it's not just the stable coin
volume they're seeing. It's the startup
world and what the startup world is
doing and how fast they're growing.
>> Let's talk about uh Stripe um maybe
through the lens of uh they purchased
Open Router uh for $78 billion uh this
past week. And for those that don't
know, Open Router is um it's an API that
allows uh anybody building an AI to
route a query to another model. So
rather than just say hey I'm using
claude or I'm using opus or um you know
chatbt it basically says hey you can now
route this to a variety of different
models. Now there's a difference between
the access to a model router which is
what open router provides and the
intelligence of which model each query
should be routed to. And um you know the
engineering team at Sylvia had this huge
announcement talking about how they
built a uh intelligence layer that
basically predicts the effort needed for
a query by looking at the first 500
characters. And so that is a kind of a
layer on top of just the model router is
also the intelligence component which
each company is having to figure out hey
how do we predict which query needs to
go to which model. Simultaneous to the
stripe story ramp which I would argue is
the closest thing to a competitor with
stripe in a different way. They're not
directly competing, but it is like the
fastest growing fintech company that
also I think people say, "Hey, that's
you know, just like Stripe." They
announced router.com, which is also the
ability to route tokens. And it feels
like everyone is coming to the
conclusion that a very valuable kind of
choke point is going to be who controls
that router. And so you have Stripe, you
have ramp all now getting into this
game. And it looks like there's going to
be a little friendly war as to, you
know, who can get which company's using
this thing.
Stripe used to be a payments company.
Then they kind of felt [clears throat]
like maybe they were becoming like a
payments company that likes stable
coins. Now they feel more just like a
tech company. Ramp on the other hand
used to be a B uh like a business uh
kind of finance management platform or
spend management platform. They you know
issue cards and do uh budgets and stuff.
Now they feel like they're kind of like
an AI research lab with the finance
component on top of it. And so how do
you just look at these companies are
evolving very quickly and they're coming
out with these new products and they're
all doing it at the same time?
It's a big win for the consumer, for the
business, you know, client. But what are
your other thoughts?
>> My other thoughts is they're betting on
the ecosystem of startups and
entrepreneurs, plain and simple. And
whether or not they're intentionally
doing that, I think they look at their
companies and let's assume that Stripe
is dealing with startup companies that
are growing rapidly. Not all of them are
going to be quote unquote AI native in
the fact that they're experts in tech.
So if you want to set up your own
sourcing and efficiency side of the cost
side of your business with AI,
it's very challenging unless you have
expertise. Jason Calcanis talks about
this all the time on the all-in pod that
in his businesses he identifies the fact
that it's fairly complicated to use open
source and use anthropic and figure a
way to do that and keep your cost down
like it's a lot of work. So, open router
um allows you and anything which is
going to do the routing side of AI
should be an offering that goes to
startup businesses in a way for them to
make sure that they're keeping their
costs efficient. Stripe is in the game
of trying to grow the ecosystem of
entrepreneurs. They are not in the
business of selling to
the big Fortune 500 companies. So the
pie of entrepreneurship is going to go
up dramatically in revenues and it's
going to be taken away from the Fortune
500 companies. I don't know how to make
that any clearer in in like my opinion
which is again the reason why I believe
in a less centralized future of
investments going forward that public
companies the bureaucracy the fact that
they're stuck on Outlook and Microsoft
and and Salesforce and all of these
things whenever people talk about well
Salesforce isn't going out of business.
No, they're not. But neither has Ford.
It doesn't mean that it's a growth
company anymore. And it doesn't mean
that they're not serving the right
people in terms of the ones that matter.
You need to be focused on
entrepreneurship right now. And so I
think Stripe is just an ecosystem
company in the same way that almost all
tech companies that have been successful
when they figure out their niche. If
Amazon is about serving
humans in in delivering stuff and also
in Amazon web, I think what Stripe is
doing is staying with inside their
channel, they're just looking at it as
entrepreneurship and the businesses, the
merchants, the companies that they do
business with. And when they get into
PayPal, which is what who they're trying
to buy, well, that's taking the
consumer's side and connecting it. So,
they're definitely a payment company.
They're definitely a crypto, you know,
financial guardrail company, but I think
they're also a business company that's
trying to grow the entrepreneurship that
fits in with AI as well.
>> Now, when you think of uh these model
routers, um do do you think that that is
a direct attack on the open AIS and the
anthropics? not not like an adversarial
way but just in terms of if you are
routing a query that means that you may
be routing them to open source or kind
of challenger model uh groups and so
that is taking revenue away from those
companies does the more we hear about
stripe and ramp and you know model
routing and and kind of the whole uh
innovation aspect of this does that feed
into the concerns around anthropic and
openai's revenue
>> well it definitely So, it's not taking
revenue away from them. Let's just say
it's reducing the share of the pie that
they're they're still growing. So, it's
really hard when a company is still
growing so fast to say that they're
losing anything. I know it's hard for
people to understand Jevans paradox, but
the reality is Jevans paradox is in play
here. So, let's say I view there being
in a simplistic way two verticals for
the open AI and anthropics. two. One is
they will get Fortune 500 company
business because they have a lot of risk
to use open source and they don't want
to get involved in the liability side,
the hacking, all of the things that'll
be associated with it. Okay. On the
other side,
you have the high-end, we need the
highest IQ side. So, Millennium on the
hedge fund side, they're not paying
Kimmy K3.0 I know to build them a risk
to work on a risk system they're using
anthropic. Um, if you want to solve
cancer, are you going to use a open-
source Chinese model with an IQ of 130
or you going to use a frontier model
with an IQ of a thousand? Um, you don't
need a thousand IQ for the majority of
tasks that are done that create revenue.
So, I think all of those tasks will
eventually go towards the open source
model. the ones that take a higher IQ
will go to those and they'll secure that
compute capacity. So there's two, you
know, there's two separate lines there
that I think people should focus on. But
if you ask me, anthropic and open AI
will keep growing. But the question is
when does their growth rate reach a
point that they start to have multiple
compression and that'll happen at some
point even if it means that the other
part that needs to be owned is it if
you're getting into solving cancer,
should you be a
public company or should you be owned by
the government? Are you like these lines
will become very blurred as we get into
the 200 IQ 2000 IQ area because if those
are the models that are doing it then
those should probably be more involved
with the governments if the governments
are getting in there and I think that
risk absolutely is real and so terminal
value becomes an issue for them because
what should a governmentowned company
trade at versus a private company
growing at 300% a quarter. um I think
you get into a different world. So
that's where I've kind of broken those
those two down. Either way, the people
that win are the ones that are able to
use open source. The routers are going
to help them. They're going to keep
their cost cheap for the next year or
two. I like companies like Palunteer
because I think the orchestration layer
becomes much much more important because
I think AI sovereignty is an issue that
also impacts anthropic and open AI. And
I think that's where Palanteer and some
of these other types of not routers but
groups that are able to use open- source
uh uh models for a company in a way
while they keep their AI sovereignty. I
recently did a uh an interview with a uh
professor of computer science at U
University of Louisville and he is the
gentleman who um he coined the term AI
safety back in 2011. Um and he's
actually very bullish on AI but very
concerned that eventually we will get to
systems that we can't control and when
we can't control them there's all these
challenges and so his belief is that the
government is now showing signs of
understanding this and they're starting
to step in. So that interview is going
to come out in a couple of days but what
I found fascinating about it is he's
also a pretty hardcore Bitcoiner for
very for a lot of the reasons that we've
talked about. um he is not really into
too much else in the crypto industry and
I explicitly asked him like are you a
Bitcoin maximalist or not and he said no
he said I just don't have time for
everything else so he you know kind of
limited time is focused on AI safety now
the reason why that becomes interesting
I think in our conversation about
anthropic and and uh and Bitcoin is what
you're really seeing here is almost
nobody has a fear of Bitcoin right there
used to be like oh is the government
going to ban it or any of this but like
pretty much every single fear of the
future in Bitcoin has dissipated and the
only thing that is debated is will it be
worth more or less in the future. Now in
the AI companies, I think every single
person is like they're definitely going
to be worth more in the future in the
sense of like they're growing, they have
revenue, they have, you know, uh um kind
of all these tailwinds, but there's a
lot of fear of what that future world
looks like. And it does feel like that
is a natural adoption point because we
saw it in Bitcoin 10 years ago. People
were scared. They they wanted to know,
you know, are we gonna like defund the
government? Is there going to be
instability, civil war? I mean, all
kinds of crazy stuff people were worried
about. I do wonder how much of the
anthropic story today of, you know, last
week or so they started talking a lot
about biotech. How much of that is cuz
they actually think there's value there
versus them trying to put out a
marketing message of like we're going to
help the human, you know, population and
it's to try to quell the fears. And if
we get in a world where all of a sudden
strategy and the product roadmap starts
getting dictated by the way it's going
to be received, these companies may look
very different 12 months from now than
they do today. Right.
>> Yeah. And and th this is an interesting
point. Um and I know this is wasn't the
direction you were going, but you you're
talking about kind of um these frontier
model companies. they really are in a in
in a way very similar to where Bitcoin
was in in the early, you know, 2010 to
2014 period. Um, number one, they're
growing fast. Their valuations have
grown bitcoinesque.
Uh, there's a tremendous amount of
speculation, but there's so much
uncertainty. And you have the
government, which is already getting
involved in their business and shutting
them down for a period of time, let them
go. it it has a lot of the similarities
that went on with Bitcoin. You have the
bubble talk, you have all of the stuff
that's gone on. So, I do believe that
this fits in with an important point,
which is this is another sign since
these are the fastest growing companies
in the history of the world
by a huge factor. There's nothing ever
close to see a company go from, you
know, such a small valuation to multiple
trillions of dollars in a matter of a
year. But that's what Anthropic has been
able to do. Uh, I think we're we're
we're witnessing something really
important in terms of again the fiat
system and what's happening to it. And
everyone should be questioning every
asset they have in their own portfolio.
And partly that's what swings over to
Bitcoin because you don't worry about it
as much, especially if it starts to make
new highs as a point of well, what are
we going to shoot against it now?
Because we've basically thrown
everything at it and nothing has
happened. even the quantum side like
they're now there's more conversation
I'm working on it but more importantly
we have so many hackings going on in the
fiat system and fears about what AI
swarms are going to be able to do which
will happen that when that happens there
it's probably going to be a positive for
Bitcoin. So that's the ironic thing
about this is the fiat system and AI
whether it's taking the power the miners
are having to do things in AI. We
haven't seen the benefit that's come
from that yet in terms of them now being
focused on the AI side because their
comput is so valuable as opposed to
making supply of Bitcoin. All of this
stuff has entered a very weird dynamic
that is all because of where AI has
gotten. And I'll continue to say you can
hear me say AI is the or Bitcoin is the
purest AI trade and stop thinking about
it from how does Bitcoin benefit from AI
and start getting into the point of how
does Bitcoin not get disrupted by AI.
And that's the point in all this stuff
is you're watching this bizarro world
where Bitcoin is coming out on the other
side maybe with less worry than
everything that's related to AI that
looks like a good investment.
>> All right, boys. I need you to pay
attention and listen. Most of you don't
realize after the age of 30,
testosterone drops about 1% a year. And
the bigger issue isn't just total
levels. There's a protein called SHBG.
Yeah, I'm in my science bag with that
one. SHBG. Then it actually binds your
testosterone and it locks it up. So even
if your number looks fine, a lot of it
isn't doing anything for you. That's
where Mars Men comes in. Mars Men is
designed to fix that. clinically dosed
ingredients that help free up bound
testosterone and support natural
production, energy, and recovery. It
works with what your body already makes,
not against it. And the feedback that
they're getting is consistent. People
are reporting more energy throughout the
day, sharper focus, better gym recovery.
It's not one-time spike. It's just
simply a higher floor. Now, this product
is made in the United States. It's
third-party tested, and it's backed by a
90-day money back guarantee. For a
limited time, our listeners can get 50%
off for life, plus free shipping, and
they'll get three free gifts, too. You
can go to mengo tomars.com. Again,
that's men gotomarss.com for 50% off and
three free gifts when you check out.
After you purchase, they will ask you
where you heard about them. Please
support our show and tell them our show
sent you. Again, men go to Mars.com. Go
check out your testosterone and fix it
if it's broke. I don't know if you saw
John Arnold, you know, probably greatest
energy trader of all time. Uh he posted
a uh a chart um this week. This is going
to blow your mind if you didn't see
this. He writes nearly three times as
many people, 44% versus 15%. So nearly
three times as many people say they'd
support a nuclear power plant being
built near where they live rather than a
data center. That is insane. And then
somebody else pointed out twice as many
people would support a coal power plant
being built near them compared to a data
center.
I mean, I saw this. I looked 14 times at
the chart to make sure that he read it
correctly. This is like crazy town we're
entering now of the fear, not even of
AI. I mean, yes, there's the fear of AI
and flock cameras and kind of that whole
thing, but we're talking specifically
about a building that you put computers
in that delivers super intelligence for
pennies to people.
I don't even know how to discuss this
anymore when I see data like this.
>> Um, you do uh
so
everything is
>> I don't think I don't think I'm allowed
to say what I think. That's the problem.
Well, let's let's just keep it this way.
I mean,
it's impossible to comprehend how much
information that we take in in our heads
because of the smartphone. Um, and how
easily our brains get programmed based
on the stuff that we read in there and
it becomes a confir confirmation bias
when you only listen to the people that
are sending the things that you want to
read and go through it. So, I don't
think people know how the human brain
works, but if it You've heard what PTSD
is. Um, to get PTSD, if you're
repetitively having a story sent to you,
no matter what, your brain starts to
change and you start saying things or
believing things that don't have to be
true. You just don't have enough
information in your head to think about
the other side. And I'll just give you
my own anecdote without naming people.
But
so, I'm an introvert. I really like to
hang around in my home. um it's hard to
get me out of it. Uh but I do like
intellectual people that provoke thought
and I I I like people that um that
really challenge me. It's one of the
reasons why I spend a lot of time in
podcasts. It's the reason why I spend a
lot of time in YouTube. But if you put
me in a room with someone who's got, you
know, I can have a conversation with
about a lot of different topics and we
can go in and out in and out. But I had
a conversation with someone over the
summertime in Maine where their views
shocked me on this issue. Shocked me.
And I said, I know for a fact that at
least 70% of what you just said to me is
not true. And the reason I know that is
cuz I spend so many hours on data
centers and I wanted to hear whether any
of what you just said is true.
this person I don't want to give their
job away and everything but let's just
say they are very high IQ graduate of
one of the best universities in the
technical universities in the country
and they literally said to me things
about data centers which are not true
including the water side and when I
brought up the fact about
do you drive by golf courses do you see
the sprinklers on every single morning
do you realize that they use more water
than a data center and the old data
centers are different than the new data
centers and things change. Where did you
get your information from? I realize
more and more in life that when I have
conversations with people once I read
this, I realize a lot of it has to do
with their government beliefs. A lot of
it has to do with their rigid brain of
what they follow and in terms of where
they're getting their news from. In this
person's case, their news comes from one
TV station and that's where they get it
all. And so I think we're in an age
where this goes on more than it's
happening. and it worries me. But I
think in the case of AI advancement,
I've actually come to the conclusion
that the good side of this is that if we
have things move too fast, bad things
happen. So in a in a world of different
opinions, regardless of where they're
coming up with their views from,
friction to some degree, when you're
moving this fast, actually might be a
positive because I think it allows human
beings to come to a uh a better
viewpoint of AI in a longer period of
time. while the advancement can't get to
the point where it's a bubble, where
everything's blowing up, where we're
building things without any rules. So,
as much as I don't think we should be
having a lot of regulation and a lot of
rules to slow it down, I do believe that
it's going at a pace which allows it to
be handled more because if not,
exponential is something human beings
can't handle and it might drive people
crazier that way.
>> Jordy, you should have just called me. I
could have told you exactly what was
going on. you were talking to you were
talking to an overeducated dumb person
[laughter] like like there's a lot of
those people out there.
>> I'm sure you've been I'm sure you've
heard from many of them in your Bitcoin
days over the last 15 years.
>> Yes. I I mean look it it is uh uh it is
true but it is also in a weird way um
you can be overeducated and it can be a
huge hurdle to understanding the current
world. And you know the example I've
given a couple of people who uh are are
very close friends of mine who maybe you
know have different views on certain
things or whatever and and I'll kind of
you know Toyota 5 them and say you know
how did you get to that conclusion and
it really will come out of like well in
college I was taught blah blah blah
whatever and I say okay that's great if
something is true today that was not
true before how long do you think it
will take to get into a college te
textbook
2 years 3 years 5 years? you know,
there's some like massive lag. And so,
if you read something in a book 10 years
ago, that really means it's probably a
belief from 15 or 20 years ago and it
was cemented in the book and then, you
know, here we go. And so, I don't know
if uh that's everybody. I I don't think
it is everybody like, you know, that
their views are just dictated by what
they read in college or something. But I
do think that there is uh a very high
correlation between the people who adopt
new technology, the people who are more
entrepreneurial, the people who update
their thinking on a constant basis. It's
like you kind of are uh almost like a
mental athlete and as a mental athlete
what do you have to do if you are
entrepreneurial or you are constantly
adopting new technology you have to be
quick on your feet you have to
constantly be updating your worldview
you have to take in new information you
have to synthesize it you have to always
be asking yourself is this true is this
real is this something that I want to
incorporate into my thought process if
you work like a nineto-ive kind of chill
job and you don't have a lot of the
mental athlete you know requirements
you can operate off of 5 years ago, you
know, uh, kind of mental framework.
Nothing really changes in your
day-to-day life. And so, you're like
quite literally unprepared for the world
that we're in today because you just
don't have the practice or the the kind
of skill set needed to update your world
view every, you know, at at the pace
we're going right now, every month, you
got to update it, right?
>> So, this is [clears throat] an important
thing and I've written a lot about this.
I I uh I spent a lot of time in my life
studying the brain. I I read Freud when
I was very young from a a psychological
basis and a psychiatric basis to
understand
who I was as a person from my
upbringing. Um we most of our brain
consumes the most information from 0 to
4, but we don't remember anything from 0
to 4. So I went into Freud and
eventually into Jung and Skinner and did
a whole bunch of reading on this stuff
to understand it. Then I wanted to
understand the way that it works so I
could understand how to make my brain
work better. Um, there were all
different types of understanding the
reason people think this way and get
caught in this trap. So I'll give people
a little background on on my
relationship with my father. My father
died recently, but he was an atheist. My
mother was a devout Catholic. So I would
sp I would go to church two or three
times a weekend. She sang in the choir.
Um, and my father told me there was no
God. So, you grow up in a house as a
young kid and you're consuming this type
of information. But the advice my father
gave me, which just shows how important
that little example was to keep my brain
open, and I'll summarize what you said
for people with Thomas Bae and with um
Annie Duke as two people to for them to
to spend time with. Uh he told me,
"Nothing you will hear in life is true
except 2 plus 2 is four." Now, that's
obviously simplified. you can go into
into into all things related to science
and get up with facts. But his point was
true. Meaning everything you'll hear
from a human being is someone's opinion.
And [snorts] if you go through life,
then it it immediately makes you in my
case when combined with my ADHD type
brain hate school because why am I
learning this? You're giving me one
person's opinion from a book. I don't
care because I want to read a thousand
people's opinions and then shape my own.
That is the beginning of a basian brain.
That is the beginning of take in new
information, change your views based on
the information you have. And then Annie
Duke, who wrote the book Thinking in
Bets, who I love to death and had a
great conversation with her on this
whole topic. Life is all about thinking
in bets. You're making bets every day of
your life, whether it's the drive you're
taking into work, whether it's the food
you choose for the day. Every single
thing you're doing is thinking in bets.
And they're all investments in in some
future outcome. And so unless you go
through life being open to new
information and changing your views in
bets that it's a constantly uh formula
that keeps changing, I think you're
going to have a really hard time right
now because the world is changing so
rapidly that if you're stuck in your
views, you become an academic in the
past. But this is what the opposite of
my father was. Everyone that did well in
school thought there was an answer to a
question. They thought there was a grade
that would get them a particular
occupation. They thought they'd make a
certain amount of money by a certain
age. that doesn't exist anymore. I can't
remember the name of the book right now.
Um, but Daniel Pink wrote a book in like
2005 or 2006 which was all about the
left, you know, the change from the
world being dominated by people that
were more mathematical and had this
whole formulaic approach and ones that
were more entrepreneurial and more
artistic. And that's what's happening.
And that's why I keep telling people it
is better to learn how to fail right
now. Fail, get back up, build something
new. fail, build something new, fail,
build something new. Then, hey, I want
to get a job at so- and so, and I want
to be at that company for the next 20
years. That that world doesn't exist
anymore. And I think it fits into what
you were saying, which is when you watch
news or you come up with an opinion.
That opinion cannot be in stone and you
can't reinforce it with sourcing people
that are going to go through it. You
have to be open to different parts. And
that's where the basian side gets in and
the Annie Duke. We're getting close to
the holidays. I say this every year. Go
buy Thinking in Bets for your kids. It
is the single best book that they can
read in terms of making sure their mind
is thinking in a world that's
exponential.
>> I love it. You uh tomorrow on Sunday are
going to issue a call to arms for the uh
Bitcoin and crypto community. Tell us
about this video that you're cooking up.
I I've said repeatedly that I'm I'm
preparing to add a crypto side to my um
to my weekly stuff on the subscribers
and it was meant to coincide and it just
happens to be the perfect timing at this
point. Uh we'll see if it stays that
way, but it was really meant for when
people came back from the summer because
I believe that we'd be entering a period
where for the rest of this year um
people would be dragged into paying
attention to Bitcoin and then the
investments would be made next year. uh
the investments being next year when we
get to the new calendar year. So, I'm
going to go through all the reasons why
because I've been waiting for the tape
to tell me the time is right. And as of
right now, the tape has spoken loudly.
It has spoken proudly. Um I will ask
everyone at 8:30 a.m. is when the video
comes out. I put this an X. It will go
out there. For those of you who are on
X, for those of you on LinkedIn, I would
greatly appreciate for this video if you
would go show it around. And let me give
you the reasons why this is not me
asking you to do something for me uh for
me. It will help me obviously just like
subscribing does. But here's the main
thing. I do these videos to get back to
the point we just said with Basian and
Annie Duke. Your kids, your friends,
your parents, everyone needs to make
sure that they understand what is about
to happen. This in my opinion is the
most important point. That's why I call
it the AO macro nexus point. AI is
disrupting the world. Bitcoin is on the
other side of it. The crypto guardrails
are being put in place. You need to
understand this in a way. I know
everyone has not read the Bitcoin white
paper and I don't expect you to, but now
you don't have a reason not to. You
don't have to read it. You just have to
upload it into Chat GPT and ask it
questions while you're walking around at
a park. It is time to understand. You
don't have to agree with Anthony and I
on on on Bitcoin in the way that we
describe it, but I think you need to be
open to accepting new information and
and possibly changing thinking and bets.
And at a minimum, if you believe there's
a 20% chance that we're right, well,
that means theoretically you should have
somewhere near 20% of your savings in
Bitcoin. If you think there's a 5%
chance, you should have 5%. But
somewhere within there, you should be
hedging out the probability or the
possibility that what we're saying is
right. And I think for everyone that
wants to kind of learn about it, I'm
going to take you on a long journey of
learning for for at least the next few
years in this.
>> Sign me up. I'm in. [laughter]
>> We're in it together, bro.
>> All right. [clears throat]
Sounds good. Thank you very much. Uh for
all the people who in the comments for
the last three, four, five, six weeks
been saying, "When is Bitcoin going to
move?" You guys keep saying Bitcoin's
not going to move 23% up in a single
week. I'm not saying it was Jordy, but I
am saying that he kind of did get it
right. So, you know, give give the man a
little bit of grace here, you weirdos in
the comments. Uh, all right. I
appreciate it.
>> You have your hoodie on for this week.
That's a telltale sign right there. So,
we're going from suit to hoodie. So,
>> I was wondering if you saw that. You You
don't know. The suit is a bare market
phenomenon. The uh uh the suit has uh
has always come out in the bare markets.
You know, you got to be a little bit
more serious. People are like, "The
thing is down. Are you Are you a serious
person?"
>> Well, you know what? I'll be back in the
uh studio next week, so I'll uh
hopefully you'll be there. I'll if not,
I'll be there with Matt and I'll get to
see whether you have the suit on or the
uh the hoodie in the library. [laughter]
>> I love it. I love it. All right, we'll
see everyone next week. See you.